# GRAPHIC DESIGNER DIGITAL DESIGNER

# LAU RA PAIS



PHONE: +351 914 478 683
E-MAIL: pais.laura@gmail.com

WEBSITE: laurapais.pt

**PORTFOLIO:** <u>laurapais.pt/portfolio.pdf</u> **LINKEDIN:** linkedin.com/in/laura-pais

## **ABOUT ME**

Laura Pais, with a Master's and a Bachelor's degree in Design and Multimedia at the University of Coimbra. Currently doing an internship at United by and with previous experience as a freelancer.

The work covers areas such as graphic, communication and editorial design, web design and web development.

With the aim of producing innovative work, I follow a working method centred on the digital domain, taking advantage of my technological knowledge to combine it with traditional design.

Strongly motivated by what I produce, I consider myself creative and committed. Beyond pixels and vectors, I'm interested in cinema, music and I love travelling.

### **EDUCATION**

2018-2021

# BACHELOR IN DESIGN AND MULTIMEDIA UNIVERSITY OF COIMBRA

Completed with an average of 17/20

Core course units: Multimedia Programming, , Typography, Project 1 — Web Identity, Typography in Digital Media, Audiovisual Production, Project 2 — Audiovisual, Project 3 — Multimedia Applications, Interactive Media Design, Project 4 — Interactive Multimedia, Introduction to Artificial Intelligence.

2021-2023

# MASTER IN DESIGN AND MULTIMEDIA UNIVERSITY OF COIMBRA

Completed with an average of 19/20

Core course units: Web Development, Communication Design Workshop, Advanced Typography, Computational Creativity for Design, Multimedia Design Workshop, Comunication and Digital Marketing, Generative Design.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

2024

#### **DESIGNER — UNITED BY**

Internship in Graphic and Communication Design, Web Design, Web Development and Motion Design at United by.

2022-2024

#### **MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER — A LESTE**

Visual Identity, Communication Design, Motion Design, Social Media Management, Web Design and Web Development for the chimney cake shop, A Leste (Freelance).

2024

#### **MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER — LIBUC**

Visual identity and Web Design for *Liga dos Amigos da Biblioteca Geral da Universidade de Coimbra.* 

2024

#### **DESIGNER GRÁFICA — ONDA PURA**

Communication design for the Wave Series 2024 event.

2024

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER — LIVRO DE HORAS**

Visual Identity and Communication Design for the exhibition Livro de Horas by Luís Maldonado at the Casa das Artes de Miranda do Corvo.

2023

#### MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER — ATELIER NUNES E PÃ

Collaboration with Atelier Nunes e Pã where visual identities, Motion Design and Web Design were developed..

2023

#### **MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER — DARQ**

Communication materials for the event *Apresentação do Projeto de Arquitetura*, Department of Architecture, University of Coimbra (Freelance).

2022-2023

#### WEBSITE MANAGEMENT — DARQ

Management of the website of the Department of Architecture of the University of Coimbra (Freelance).

2022

## MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER MC HOSPITALITY ADVISORS

Visual identity, Web Design and Web Development for MC Hospitality Advisors (Freelance).

2021

#### MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER CICLO DE CONVERSAS DESIGN + MULTIMÉDIA

Visual identity, Web Design, Web Development and Communication Design for the 2021 edition of the *Ciclo de Conversas Design + Multimédia* (Freelance).

### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Adobe InDesign
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Premiere
Adobe Lightroom
Adobe After Effects
Adobe Photoshop

Figma
HTML
CSS
JavaScript
P5.js
Processing

### **LANGUAGES**

Português — Native Language Inglês — Fluent

### **AWARDS**

2024

**Best Thesis Award** — 'Graphic Ground: Modular generative system for visual communication materials', master's thesis, was honoured with the Best Thesis Award from the Portuguese Association for the Development of Communications (APDC) in the Media category.